Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 102.
And this exercise, we are going to create the linear search algorithm inside Java.
So how to make a linear search function that go through an array and search for a specific element?
If this found or not using the linear search, it's very simple and we have done this in the array section.
But in this material, I will go deeply and be specific in the linear search.
So and thus sources.
I would go to the algorithms and click on Java class and create a new linear search.
Okay, so
we start by making here.
Public static int linear search, we need to return the index of the element in the array where we have
found the element inside it or not.
So int array that we are going to search inside it and index that we are going to search for.
We start by making it an equal to at a dog length for going through array sequentially, so going through
they sequentially.
See when.
Sequin.
Shelly.
OK, so Ford and I equal to zero.
We start from zero I less than an eye plus plus than we make if.
Are they at Index II equal equal to X, then we to.
I mean, otherwise if we don't find anything, then we need to return minus one.
And this is why we have created the end.
They're returning Typekit.
So we will return the index if it is found otherwise.
If is not found, we return minus one.
So if it is.
Not found where to turn minus one.
OK.
It's very simple exercise, but I should mention it because we need to compare it with binary search
in the next video.
So public static void,
main string args
and we start inthe array.
One or two, Steve.
These are the numbers
and an X equal to one.
I need to search for one end result, equal to linear search.
I will.
But the returning value of calling this function inside a variable called the result, so I will pass
the array that we are going to search for inside it and that x that we are going to search for.
So we are looking wine for X, which is equal to one in the array, which is these numbers are incomplete.
So if the result equal equal to minus one, then we bring the system out that print and element not
fact.
Otherwise, we will print them out to print and the element
found at index
clusters.
Let's run and see, and here we go.
We have that element not found.
Let me try number six.
That's right.
And here we go, element found at index two, zero, one and two.
So this is that linear search.
I told you that it is complexity is Oh, do.
And look, it's all of and because it depends on how many numbers inside the array that we are going
to search for a specific.
So it contains 100.
It was its complexity would be 100.
And we are searching for 100 in the worst case.